Ethan Zimmermann

(708) 945-6734 || ethan.a.zimmermann@gmail.com || 2904 Milwaukee St. Atpt. 3, Madison WI 53704

Objective

To leverage my dedication to foolproof design, clean code, and optimal development as well as my 5 years of experience in software engineering into a Senior Developer role at Nordic Consulting, where I can positively impact both my workspace and the rest of the healthcare field.

Education

Special Degree student | University of Wisconsin, Madison | 2016

· Attended a Human and Computer Interactions course through the UW Madison CS department.

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | OBERLIN COLLEGE | 2014

- · Major: Computer Science
- · Related coursework: Studied Computer Science along with Neuroscience, Economics, and Psychology.

Related Experience

Application developer | Evident change | nov 2018 - present

- Managed a variety of projects as the primary develop over 22 releases aimed at providing end user requested enhancements and improvements to legacy code
- · Designed and developed two .NET Core API's from the ground-up for consumption by third party software
- · Created numerous Vue.js and Angular demo applications using different add-ons and frameworks, including Nuxt, Vuex, Composition API, and Single-SPA.js, in order to help the dev team determine which framework to pursue for new development
- · Constructed Azure Pipelines in Azure DevOps for a number of Microfrontend projects as well as root Nuxt application with the purpose of using Infrastructure as Code in new development

DATA EXTRACTION ANALYST | FLOATING POINT FX LLC | Aug. 2018 - Nov. 2018

 Extracted geographical data from 3D meshing collections from LiDAR and other data sources to provide customers with efficient neighborhood layouts

INTEGRATION ENGINEER | EPIC SYSTEMS | SEPT. 2015 - FEB. 2018

- Worked as a full stack developer on Epic's <u>App Orchard</u> project, creating and maintaining admin
 workflows and the submission process as well as other end-user facing screens while also maintaining
 database configuration and implementing site security
- · Converted multiple EDI workflow pages from VB6 to a .NET-based platform in order to keep the team's technology up to date with Epic's standards
- · Designed and implemented new pages and workflows within the EDI workspace, including a means for end-users to more easily navigate unforeseen errors

• Supported Epic customers in implementing and maintaining Epic Interfaces to ensure the customer's instance of Epic communicated appropriately with third party systems

WEB DEVELOPER | OBERLIN COLLEGE ENVIRONMENTAL STUDIES DEPT. | 2013 - 2014

· Designed and developed a website for a professor's energy conservation project

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN \mid PC REBUILDERS AND RECYCLES \mid 2012

- Built PC's for the company to reconfigure, format, and distribute
- · Wrote shell scripts to improve the efficiency of the formatting workflow
- Developed enhancements in the company's internal site in order to make department communication easier

Additional Experience

Special education teacher | leslie lewis elementary | 2014 - 2015

- · Taught 19 fourth and fifth graders with IEP's in a Resource Room
- · Compiled Common Core-based lesson plans scaffolded to meet students' learning needs

Skills & Abilities

DEVELOPMENT

· .NET Core | .NET Web Forms | Vue.js | Nuxt | Angular | SQL IIS | Azure Devops | Bootstrap | Tailwind | Javascript | Typescript | Knockout | Cache | PHP | HTML | Ruby on Rails | Shell | Python | Java | C++

Technologies

Oracle DB | IIS Management | Visual Studio 2015-2019 | Visual Studio Code | Azure Devops |
 Kubernetes | Lerna | SQL Server Management Studio | Balsamiq | Wordpress

Frameworks and Strategies

· Infrastructure-as-Code Strategies | Active Directory Design and Development | User-Centric Design

Looking for primarily a backend developer